<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-11T10:43:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Elias Augustus Brough</title><subtitle>The war diary and ephemera of Elias Augustus Brough, Private, 6th Australian Field Ambulance</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sunday, 25/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/25/sunday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunday, 25/11/17" /><published>1917-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/25/sunday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/25/sunday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Psalm 84-1 &quot;How amiable /are
thy tabernacles, O Lord of hosts?&quot;
This was a busy + exciting day
Long grey lines could be seen
along the horizon, now + then
a small island would be passed
with occasional fishing smacks sailing
past + soon in the distance an
outline of South America also of
North America could be seen.
As we neared the long looked for
Panama. At the entrance we passed
a small Island
+ was soon met by
the American Pilot who in his
fast going motor boat span
round us before + behind
Soon he was aboard + took
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small sketch presumably of the island&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;charge of the boat
we were informed that we
would not pass through
till the morrow as the trip
takes from 8-12 hours.
As we neared the mouth of
the canal I was very much
struck with the uncommon
yet beautiful green of the
vegetation.
Long before this we had seen
the glimmer of the lighthouse
which stood out on the first point
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hand-drawn map showing South America, Mexico, Panama, Tolagedo and the path of the ship, Aeneas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;to the right of this point
tucked snugly
away in the breasts of
the surrounding hills
which were covered
with a brilliant verdure
of green grass + tropical
vegetation lay veritable
fairy town called
&quot;Tolagedo&quot;. This town
is said to be used as a
'German Internment Camp'
I felt half envious of
men who could be interned
under such beautiful
conditions.
Directly opposite on
Starboard side but more 
to the north lay the

City of Panama.
As a hill came between 
us and Panama we did
not see a great deal of
that famous city.
It appeared to be a fair
size bigger than Hobart
+ nicely laid out. Trams,
trains + motors beside
a few donkeys + mules were
the chief means of
conveyance but we did
not see these things until
the 26th as we had to
lie outside until the morning.
You may be sure all
were about early the
next morning as all

were anxious to see
what they could of this
World renowned canal.
Even the sweet sleeps
of this humble were
intruded upon + he too
was out to see what
was going on.
Unfortunately the Ward
was pretty full of patients
some of whom were
pretty sick.
About 7am the anchor was pulled up
and we began to ascend
the mouth of the Canal
We were soon surrounded
by the brilliant hills
+ scenery + as the

banks narrowed we were
soon conversing with
the natives.
Among one of the first
question asked by our boys
was. Who won the Melbourne
cup? The natives looked
so innocent of racing
+ ignorant of Melbourne
that this called forth quite
a laugh of mirth on the
part of our boys.
Soon we found ourselves
within the narrow locks.
Think what it meant to us
who had read, thought,
conversed, pictured + to say
nothing of the excitation of
the canal. To be here

+ actually gazing upon
the object of so much
previous debate.
I must give here a very brief
account as to my observations
were rather intruded upon
having duties that could not
be overlooked.
(a) Steam was shut off.
(b) The locks were very narrow.
(c) Water, on entering the locks 
was often shallow.
(d) Boats waited until the 
water entered the lock
(e) Locks were quickly filled 
when flood gates opened.
(f) The usual depth of water 
passed on by the flood
gates were 60-80 ft.

(g) Parallel to the main locks are 
'linergery locks' kept in
case of flood gates bursting
(h) Flood gates made of solid
steel.
(i) Progress of boat through the
locks depended on six
steel mules (electric)
three on either side. One in
front right and centre.
(j) At places the locks widened
+ we passed quite a number
of Yankee boats, steamers and
Merchantmen.
k. As we passed each strange
boat, the strange gave
three sharp blasts. When
we had passed them by +
not till then, did the Aen

return the Salute by giving
three blasts in return.
Opposite the town of Panama
the people crowded out to
see us. The Yankee soldiers
who were there in great
numbers cheered, conversed
+ exchanged mementos +
articles of clothing with
our boys. Here, I regret to
say that many of the
badges exchanged by our
lads were not their own
property; but that of their
mates. But such is the
ease with a mixed crowed.
It was also apparent that
some of the boys lost their
&quot;block&quot; + gave away what

they could ill afford.
e.g. One dropped, to a young
lady who took his eye. This
wristlet watch. Another in
his excitement discarded
his money belt containing
£2 notes + threw over and
many of their similar cases could
be recorded. Of course these
boys later regretted their
rash deeds. It's a good thing
to cultivate self control
under all circumstances.
I threw over an A.M.C
badge but as it bounded
back into the lock I am
afraid that no one would
profit by my liberality.
As we entered each lock

the boat would be of
necessity stationary for
about 20 minutes or more
for the water to come in.
At each stop the people
came out + on one occasion
English ladies + gentlemen
threw aboard apples
chocolate + papers. Just
when I thought my luck
was out a nice box of
chocolates landed at my
feet. Great was the rush
thereupon but your
'humble' servant secured
+ enjoyed the contents
with some friends.
With thanks to the donor.

The names + sizes of locks.
These are dealt with in
Views of Panama already forwarded.
It would be well to add
here that the lake in the
centre was a great asset
in the construction of this
mighty piece of Workmanship.
It is of a pretty big extent
though, I think that the
canal itself has added
to the waters thereof.
The landslip which contrib-
uted so much to the labour
+ delay in opening the
Canal was of huge
dimensions + workmen
are still engaged along

the banks securing it
from further slides.
The site of the old canal
also came into view +
showed the failure of the
previous Engineer in
choosing his course.
The continuous work of
inundation + filtering of
sediment by the outflow
of streams + rivulets
add to the great upkeep
of the canal.

The Position of Panama.
As can be readily seen
from the Map: Panama
seems to be the spot
which the &quot;Designer&quot; of
the Universe would have
in mind for the cutting
which would unite
the pathways of Europe
to Australia by so many
thousand of miles.
Many thousands of lives
were lost in this under-
taking as is well known,
by the fatal Malaria.
Many millions of gallons
of Paraffin were sprayed
on the surrounding
district before the

deadly disease had been
sufficiently combated.
Its origins is not now
disputed + the deadly
mosquito's life is in
jeopardy.
I have mentioned the
luxuriant tropical
vegetations. I will now
mention a tropical
shower.
Although the sun rose
in beautiful lustre, de-
picting a hot day yet
we noticed that the
people, both black + white
carried umbrellas + this
peculiar incident called
forth many mirthful

laughs + jests.
e.g. Say, Darkie, are you
afraid of the sun tanning
your face?
Why do you carry these big
palm umbrellas + not use
them, they are clumsy walk-
ing sticks?
Ere the afternoon was
spent we found that our
wisdom lacked
knowledge and their
folly proved wisdom.
About 2.pm. I ran up
on deck to recover some
orderly whose inquisitiveness
had overcome him + consequence
by he had eloped.
The sun was pouring forth

his rays from a cloudless
yet sultry sky when
suddenly the eyes of the
landsmen turned upward
+ almost immediately
the huge cumbersome
umbrellas were also turned
up, simultaneously great
drops began to fall and
before we could take
cover we were all drenched
through to the skin.
The like of these drops +
the mode of their falling
could only be pictured
from an Australian
thunderstorm which appears
without clouds.
I made down for my

cabin + having only two
uniforms aboard reluctantly
clad my self in my &quot;Sunday
go-Meeting attire&quot; a
circumstance which I was
to very sorely regret before
the night was out.
Naturally many cases of colds
+ more than one pneumonia
were the results of the Tropical
shower yet we were
thankful there were not
more.
The People of Panama.
I cannot let my notes on this
wonderful place conclude
without a few notes on the
people
On coming among the U.S.A.

soldiers + the people one of our own boys
is trying to be observed shouted &quot;What do
you think of Australian soldiers _here_?&quot;
I am glad that the ignorance displayed by
this boy in trying to count favour for
Australians in this way was quickly suppressed
+ such taunts arose from our boys that
he ought never to be heard again on a
voyage. The white people evidently do no
work, the labour is black. Whites look
delicate, dreadfully so. Most have the
Yankee twang. The Niggers were
most enthusiastic in their welcome +
good wishes. Many asking us to give the
Germans no quarter until they were
completely beaten. All of their Women with
huge families became every excited +
gave vent to their feelings by shouting,
raising hands above their heads + swaying
from side to side. &quot;Continued see Heading Below&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How amiable are thy tabernacles, O Lord of hosts?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Psalm 84:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a busy and exciting day. Long grey lines could be seen along the horizon, now and then a small island would be passed  with occasional fishing smacks sailing past + soon in the distance an outline of South America also of North America could be seen as we neared the long looked for Panama. At the entrance we passed a small Island and was soon met by the American Pilot who in his fast going motor boat span round us before and behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[A small sketch presumably of the island]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon he was aboard and took charge of the boat. We were informed that we would not pass through till the morrow as the trip takes from 8-12 hours. As we neared the mouth of the canal I was very much struck with the uncommon yet beautiful green of the vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Hand-drawn map showing South America, Mexico, Panama, Tolagedo and the path of the ship, Aeneas.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long before this we had seen the glimmer of the lighthouse which stood out on the first point. To the right of this point tucked snugly away in the breasts of the surrounding hills which were covered with a brilliant verdure of green grass and tropical vegetation lay veritable fairy town called “Tolagedo”. This town is said to be used as a ‘German Internment Camp’. I felt half envious of men who could be interned under such beautiful conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly opposite on Starboard side but more  to the north lay the City of Panama. As a hill came between  us and Panama we did not see a great deal of that famous city. It appeared to be a fair size bigger than Hobart and nicely laid out. Trams, trains and motors beside a few donkeys and mules were the chief means of conveyance but we did not see these things until the 26th as we had to lie outside until the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be sure all were about early the next morning as all were anxious to see what they could of this World renowned canal. Even the sweet sleeps of this humble were intruded upon and he too was out to see what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the Ward was pretty full of patients some of whom were pretty sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 7am the anchor was pulled up and we began to ascend the mouth of the Canal. We were soon surrounded by the brilliant hills and scenery and as the banks narrowed we were soon conversing with the natives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among one of the first question asked by our boys was, “Who won the Melbourne Cup?”” The natives looked so innocent of racing and ignorant of Melbourne that this called forth quite a laugh of mirth on the part of our boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon we found ourselves within the narrow locks. Think what it meant to us who had read, thought, conversed, pictured and to say nothing of the excitation of the canal. To be here and actually gazing upon the object of so much previous debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must give here a very brief account as to my observations were rather intruded upon having duties that could not be overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steam was shut off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The locks were very narrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water, on entering the locks was often shallow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Boats waited until the water entered the lock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Locks were quickly filled when flood gates opened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The usual depth of water passed on by the flood gates were 60-80 ft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parallel to the main locks are ‘linergery locks’ kept in case of flood gates bursting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flood gates made of solid steel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Progress of boat through the locks depended on six steel mules (electric) three on either side. One in front right and centre.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At places the locks widened and we passed quite a number of Yankee boats, steamers and Merchantmen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As we passed each strange boat, the stranger gave three sharp blasts. When we had passed them by and not till then, did the Aeneas return the Salute by giving three blasts in return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opposite the town of Panama the people crowded out to see us. The Yankee soldiers who were there in great numbers cheered, conversed and exchanged mementos and articles of clothing with our boys. Here, I regret to say that many of the badges exchanged by our lads were not their own property; but that of their mates. But such is the ease with a mixed crowed. It was also apparent that some of the boys lost their “block” + gave away what they could ill afford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;e.g. One dropped, to a young lady who took his eye his wristlet watch. Another in his excitement discarded his money belt containing £2 notes and threw over and many of their similar cases could be recorded. Of course these boys later regretted their rash deeds. It’s a good thing to cultivate self control under all circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I threw over an A.M.C badge but as it bounded back into the lock I am afraid that no one would profit by my liberality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we entered each lock the boat would be of necessity stationary for about 20 minutes or more for the water to come in. At each stop the people came out and on one occasion English ladies and gentlemen threw aboard apples, chocolate and papers. Just when I thought my luck was out a nice box of chocolates landed at my feet. Great was the rush thereupon but your ‘humble’ servant secured and enjoyed the contents with some friends. With thanks to the donor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-names-and-sizes-of-locks&quot;&gt;The names and sizes of locks.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are dealt with in Views of Panama already forwarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be well to add here that the lake in the centre was a great asset in the construction of this mighty piece of Workmanship. It is of a pretty big extent though, I think that the canal itself has added to the waters thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The landslip which contributed so much to the labour and delay in opening the Canal was of huge dimensions and workmen are still engaged along the banks securing it from further slides. The site of the old canal also came into view and showed the failure of the previous Engineer in choosing his course. The continuous work of inundation and filtering of sediment by the outflow of streams and rivulets add to the great upkeep of the canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-position-of-panama&quot;&gt;The Position of Panama.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be readily seen from the Map: Panama seems to be the spot which the “Designer” of the Universe would have in mind for the cutting which would unite the pathways of Europe to Australia by so many thousand of miles. Many thousands of lives were lost in this undertaking as is well known, by the fatal Malaria. Many millions of gallons of Paraffin were sprayed on the surrounding district before the deadly disease had been sufficiently combated. Its origins is not now disputed and the deadly mosquito’s life is in jeopardy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have mentioned the luxuriant tropical vegetations. I will now mention a tropical shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the sun rose in beautiful lustre, depicting a hot day yet we noticed that the people, both black and white carried umbrellas and this peculiar incident called forth many mirthful laughs and jests.
e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Say, Darkie, are you afraid of the sun tanning your face?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Why do you carry these big palm umbrellas and not use them, they are clumsy walking sticks?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ere the afternoon was spent we found that our wisdom lacked knowledge and their folly proved wisdom. About 2.pm. I ran up
on deck to recover some orderly whose inquisitiveness had overcome him and consequence by he had eloped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was pouring forth his rays from a cloudless yet sultry sky when suddenly the eyes of the landsmen turned upward and almost immediately the huge cumbersome umbrellas were also turned up, simultaneously great drops began to fall and before we could take cover we were all drenched through to the skin. The like of these drops and the mode of their falling could only be pictured from an Australian thunderstorm which appears without clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made down for my cabin and having only two uniforms aboard reluctantly clad my self in my “Sunday go-Meeting attire” a circumstance which I was to very sorely regret before the night was out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally many cases of colds and more than one pneumonia were the results of the Tropical shower yet we were thankful there were not more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-people-of-panama&quot;&gt;The People of Panama.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot let my notes on this wonderful place conclude without a few notes on the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On coming among the U.S.A. soldiers and the people one of our own boys is trying to be observed shouted “What do you think of Australian soldiers &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;?” I am glad that the ignorance displayed by this boy in trying to count favour for Australians in this way was quickly suppressed and such taunts arose from our boys that he ought never to be heard again on a voyage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The white people evidently do no work, the labour is black. Whites look delicate, dreadfully so. Most have the Yankee twang. The Niggers were most enthusiastic in their welcome and good wishes. Many asking us to give the Germans no quarter until they were completely beaten. All of their Women with huge families became every excited and gave vent to their feelings by shouting, raising hands above their heads and swaying from side to side. “Continued see Heading Below”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/24.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/24.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/24.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/24.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/24.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/24.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 24, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/25.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/25.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/25.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/25.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/25.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/25.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 25, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/26.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/26.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/26.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/26.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/26.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/26.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 26, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/27.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/27.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/27.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/27.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/27.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/27.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 27, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/28.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/28.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/28.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/28.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/28.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/28.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 28, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/29.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/29.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/29.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/29.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/29.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/29.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 29, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/30.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/30.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/30.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/30.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/30.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/30.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 30, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/31.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/31.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/31.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/31.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/31.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/31.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 31, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/32.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/32.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/32.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/32.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/32.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/32.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 32, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/33.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/33.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/33.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/33.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/33.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/33.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 33, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/34.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/34.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/34.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/34.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/34.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/34.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 34, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/35.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/35.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/35.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/35.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/35.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/35.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 35, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/36.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/36.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/36.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/36.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/36.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/36.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 36, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/37.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/37.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/37.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/37.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/37.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/37.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 37, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/38.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/38.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/38.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/38.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/38.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/38.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 38, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/39.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/39.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/39.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/39.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/39.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/39.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 39, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/40.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/40.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/40.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/40.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/40.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/40.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 40, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/41.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/41.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/41.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/41.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/41.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/41.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 41, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/42.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/42.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/42.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/42.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/42.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/42.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 42, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Friday, 23/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/23/friday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Friday, 23/11/17" /><published>1917-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/23/friday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/23/friday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Psalm 100-1:2 Make a joyful noise unto the
Lord, all ye lands
Serve the Lord with gladness: come before
his presence with singing.
When shall we pass the line
when shall we cross the Equator? Was
the question on the lips of many for
several days prior to the 23rd
It is the usual procedure on board
vessels to have sort of &quot;initiation&quot; in
passing the line. This, in previous
trips I've taken a somewhat serious
turn + after having the hose turned
on you 'ducked' into a bath of cold
water fully dressed, beladded with sand
shovels etc etc. you come through the
ordeal no better for having parsed the
line but sometimes very much worse.

Hence it was decided that when
the &quot;Aineas&quot; crossed the line there
would be no initiation ceremony.
I was at work in the ward in the p.m.
on the 23rd wondering where we
were + when we should see land
looking no doubt like a lonely
sparrow on a clothes line on a snowing
day when when the Major smiling like
the rising moon on a frosty night,
especially at sea, advanced + in
his tenderest tones asked
Cpl did you know that we are to
cross the line this pm? &quot;No Sir. At
what time are we to pass over? &quot;At
dinner time probably 5.30pm&quot;
So at 5.20 pm we crossed the line
without any ado, no even a cheer, to
many a mate of sadness for did

it not mean a leaving of the south
behind, even the dear old Southern Cross
that beacon of light known from
childhood with us familiar memories
    Crossing the Line
    The line is crossed.
No sound. no stir to tell
    That we are leaving far behind
    The place we love to dwell.
But into fields anew we go
With dauntless friends; to face the foe
Who wronged us, wrenched us
From our homes, our loves
And all that we held dear.
    EAB Original
Having crossed the line we were
told that a couple of days would bring
us to sight of land. Early next day
word came into the ward that

something was seen on the horizon
Many guesses were made but
with my glasses (thanks to Ellendale
School children) I swept the
horizon + exclaimed &quot;a schooner!&quot;
I was right, soon she hove in
sight her white sails shining
on the blue ocean as pearls
shine on a golden background.
Soon a grey line was seen
on the horizon again a call
for the glasses &quot;Land&quot; I declared
It seemed so high that land was
improbable but soon it stood out
+ was evidently a rock at least 3000ft,
appeared like a cloud
in the distance but
soon became visible
we veered to the right
+ left it doing it's sentinel
work on the Port side.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Illustration in the bottom right corner of a cliff, labelled:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Rock 3000 ft high
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Make a joyful noise unto the Lord, all ye lands. Serve the Lord with gladness: come before his presence with singing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Psalm 100:1-2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When shall we pass the line, when shall we cross the Equator? Was the question on the lips of many for several days prior to the 23rd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the usual procedure on board vessels to have sort of “initiation” in passing the line. This, in previous trips I’ve taken a somewhat serious turn and after having the hose turned on you ‘ducked’ into a bath of cold water fully dressed, beladded with sand shovels etc etc. you come through the ordeal no better for having parsed the line but sometimes very much worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence it was decided that when the “Aeneas” crossed the line there would be no initiation ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at work in the ward in the p.m. on the 23rd wondering where we were and when we should see land looking no doubt like a lonely sparrow on a clothes line on a snowing day when when the Major smiling like the rising moon on a frosty night, especially at sea, advanced and in his tenderest tones asked,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Corporal did you know that we are to cross the line this pm?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No Sir. At what time are we to pass over?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At dinner time probably 5:30pm”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at 5.20 pm we crossed the line without any ado, no even a cheer, to many a mate of sadness for did it not mean a leaving of the south behind, even the dear old Southern Cross that beacon of light known from childhood with us familiar memories&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;crossing-the-line&quot;&gt;Crossing the Line&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line is crossed.&lt;br /&gt;
No sound. no stir to tell&lt;br /&gt;
That we are leaving far behind&lt;br /&gt;
The place we love to dwell.&lt;br /&gt;
But into fields anew we go&lt;br /&gt;
With dauntless friends; to face the foe&lt;br /&gt;
Who wronged us, wrenched us&lt;br /&gt;
From our homes, our loves&lt;br /&gt;
And all that we held dear.&lt;br /&gt;
— EAB Original&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having crossed the line we were told that a couple of days would bring us to sight of land. Early next day word came into the ward that something was seen on the horizon. Many guesses were made but with my glasses (thanks to Ellendale School children) I swept the horizon and exclaimed “a schooner!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was right, soon she hove in sight her white sails shining on the blue ocean as pearls shine on a golden background. Soon a grey line was seen on the horizon, again a call for the glasses. “Land” I declared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seemed so high that land was improbable but soon it stood out and was evidently a rock at least 3000 ft, appeared like a cloud in the distance but soon became visible. We veered to the right and left it doing it’s sentinel work on the Port side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/20.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/20.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/20.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/20.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/20.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/20.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 20, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/21.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/21.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/21.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/21.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/21.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/21.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 21, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/22.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/22.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/22.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/22.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/22.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/22.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 22, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/23.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/23.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/23.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/23.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/23.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/23.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 23, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Recollections on 1/1/18</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/20/recollections.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recollections on 1/1/18" /><published>1917-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/20/recollections</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/20/recollections.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Psalm 86-1
&quot;Bow down thine ear O Lord,
hear me: for I am poor + needy.&quot;
My daily notes ceased on the
17/11/17 owing to pressure of
work, inconvenient time for
note making, being confined
most of the time to the
Ward from which I derived
great pleasure through very
little excitement.
That is nearly a month ago
+ after relying on a few
specific notes such as date of
passing Panama etc. I must
fall back on memory for
the writing up of the principal
experiences on the 'Aeneas'

From the 7th onward there
was a good deal of excitement
due to preparing + having the
Ship's sports. Off course I was
on the outside of all this excepting
that it was necessary to
continually have a man on duty
to treat wounds occurring during
these notorious sports. At meal
times, at night, during duty hrs
there was the constant call
for attention to a sprained knee,
a barked shin, nose, black eye
langed cheeks, strained sinews
in back, legs, arms, wrists
anywhere, everywhere that it
was possible to get hurt,
but + bruised heads were indeed
a speciality to say nothing of

rendering 1st aid to a knocked
out man. They called it
fun but when a man has
fought so often, so long +
so hard that he is bereft
of the &quot;light of day&quot; the skin
from his face, knuckles
shins, + feet, to say nothing
of the bruises about head +
+ body then I consider it
is no longer fun, but brutal
determination.
Such is the picture of one
whose photographs one of my
orderlies took outside hospital
A living monument of the
old days of the gladiators.
Yet these say we are more
civilised to day than they were

Though so much may be said
against this form of sport yet
this is the grim determination that
has made nations, that has
made our boys do heroic works
in face of hardship, peril + death.
This is the style of determination
we must + do admire. Without
it one would be a laggard,
backless, heartless + powerless
Thanks for determination + pet
character, they are the greatest
assets next to the Grace of God
for a young man entering thus
on life.
&quot;Sports&quot; was the general topic
day in + day out with little to
cause an interruption unless it
was a fire alarm which usually

took place about 4-30pm Sat
afternoons. Occasionally rumours
would tell of a boat being sighted
but none ever came into view.
Excitement was caused when a rumour
said that a German destroyer with
the disguise of a four masted schooner
was only three days journey ahead
+ had sunk two American boats.
This could not have been true though
Sister Calvin assured me that the
'Wireless Operator' had told her; but I
think it was told in order to make
us careful about lights etc. One
thing is certain. The route of the
'Aeneas' was a zigzag + we often
noted that we were travelling
a SE course + then due N when
we should have been going a NE course.

During all this time the Hos remained
pretty full. Capt Speirs was a most
amenable man with whom to work. Spoke
to me once only saying &quot;no patient should
go up on deck until after his rest.&quot; He
would do anything for the Hos or the
patients + I am now sorry that I did
not utilise more of his amiable nature
regarding myself + the patients. He said
that he left me entirely responsible
for the ward + I felt that + acted
accordingly. Nevertheless, he was not at
ease until SSB was disrated + out of
it. I was glad that my evidence on
the case tho against him + strictly true,
did not change his attitude toward 
me.
Major Rosenfield though of Jewish birth + of
peculiar manner proved himself a

gentleman + friend throughout the
whole trouble to SSB not only so
he was extremely good to me, taking
the 1st opportunity to put me on full
pay saying &quot;I deserved it&quot; Here I
was honoured being the only N.C.O of
the AAMC to receive payment though
there were quite a lot of NCOs
made VO
When I had trouble with the Night
Steward regarding my night
orderlies food + I was told by him
to keep my mouth shut, which often
I did do so did not fill my orderlies
mouths, he, the Major hastened to
my assistance had the Night Steward
paraded before him + me + the Chief
Steward told the night Steward that
I was a &quot;gentleman&quot; + was known to him

as also said the Chief Steward + that I
was not to be spoken to like that by him
or anyone else + that I could have
whatever I asked for.
The poor Steward tried to defend
himself but my evidence was far too
strong for him as my boys had been
suffering for weeks through his
bad temper, due, I believe because
they did not tip him. yet I felt
sorry when the Chief would not
allow him to speak saying it must
have been serious when the Hos Cpl
complained + if there was another
murmur he would know what awaited
him at the end of voyage.
The poor night boys who had suffered
agonies at his hands with beaming
faces thanked me for the result.

We still steam ahead the atmosphere
getting warmer as we approached
the Equator. At time it was
fairly warm but not nearly so
hot as I expected. Many where
the exclamations + wishes to see land
only to see Mother Earth once
more. After 21 days of Sea blue 
sea, green sea, smooth
sea. rough sea. quiet + peaceful
as a mill pond, rough +
boisterous as Biscay Sea with
sun shining on it: with moon
+ stars. Stars that we had
known, dipping to the south
reminding us of separation
from home and friends
Silver sea, sparkling sea.
dark sea blackness that I could

almost feel Sea to the front to
the back below + all round us
day after day, week after week
sea eternal sea with nothing
on the horizon (landscape) save an occasional
bird + a darting flying fish.
Horizon, thou teller of falsehood
have often didst thou seem within
an hours steam + yet we drew
no nearer to you, as we crept
along, so didst thou skip
away with no object other than
to deceive our sight.
Well might early explorers have
been afraid of you not knowing
what thou helds't beyond
that deceiving line. Many
thought of hobgoblins depths
of misery, perpendicular heights

over which one might fall never
to return.
Sea, sea, sea;
So dark and lonesome!
Speak through the gloom to me
Of joy and love and home.
Tell of hearts that are burning
Of souls that are yearning
Over the dark sea
Praying for me.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bow down thine ear, O Lord, hear me: for I am poor and needy.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Psalm 86:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My daily notes ceased on the 17/11/17 owing to the pressure of work, inconvenient time for note making, being confined most of the time to the ward from which I derived great pleasure though very little excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is nearly a month ago and after relying on a few specific notes such as the date of passing Panama, etc. I must fall back on memory for the writing up of the principal experiences on the ‘Aeneas’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the 7th onward there was a good deal of excitement due to preparing and having the Ship’s sports. Of course I was on the outside of all this excepting that it was necessary to continually have a man on duty to treat wounds occurring during these notorious sports. At meal times, at night, during duty hours there was the constant call for attention to a sprained knee, a barked shin, nose, black eye, langed[?] cheeks, strained sinews in the back, legs, arms, wrists, anywhere, everywhere that it was possible to get hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But and bruised heads were indeed a speciality to say nothing of rendering first aid to a knocked out man. They called it fun but when a man has fought so often, so long and so hard that he is bereft of the “light of day”, the skin from his face, knuckles shins, and feet, to say nothing of the bruises about head and body. Then I consider it is no longer fun, but brutal determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such is the picture of one whose photographs one of my orderlies took outside hospital. A living monument of the old days of the gladiators. Yet these say we are more civilised to day than they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though so much may be said against this form of sport yet this is the grim determination that has made nations, that has made our boys do heroic works in face of hardship, peril, and death. This is the style of determination we must and do admire. Without it one would be a laggard, backless, heartless and powerless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for determination + pet? character, they are the greatest assets next to the Grace of God for a young man entering thus on life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sports” was the general topic day in + day out with little to cause an interruption unless it was a fire alarm which usually took place about 4:30 pm Saturday afternoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally rumours would tell of a boat being sighted but none ever came into view. Excitement was caused when a rumour said that a German destroyer with the disguise of a four masted schooner was only three days journey ahead and had sunk two American boats. This could not have been true though Sister Calvin assured me that the ‘Wireless Operator’ had told her; but  think it was told in order to make us careful about lights etc. One thing is certain. The route of the ‘Aeneas’ was a zigzag + we often noted that we were travelling a SE course and then due N when we should have been going a NE course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all this time the Hospital remained pretty full. Captain Speirs was a most amenable man with whom to work. Spoke to me once only saying “no patient should go up on deck until after his rest.” He would do anything for the Hospital or the patients and I am now sorry that I did not utilise more of his amiable nature regarding myself and the patients. He said that he left me entirely responsible for the ward and I felt that and acted accordingly. Nevertheless, he was not at ease until SSB was disrated and out of it. I was glad that my evidence on the case though against him and strictly true, did not change his attitude toward me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major Rosenfield though of Jewish birth and of peculiar manner proved himself a gentleman and friend throughout the whole trouble to SSB not only so he was extremely good to me, taking the first opportunity to put me on full pay saying “I deserved it”. Here I was honoured being the only N.C.O of the AAMC to receive payment though there were quite a lot of NCOs made VO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I had trouble with the Night Steward regarding my night orderlies food and I was told by him to keep my mouth shut, which often I did do so did not fill my orderlies mouths, he, the Major, hastened to my assistance had the Night Steward paraded before him and me and the Chief Steward told the night Steward that I was a “gentleman” and was known to him as also said the Chief Steward and that I was not to be spoken to like that by him or anyone else and that I could have whatever I asked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor Steward tried to defend himself but my evidence was far too strong for him as my boys had been suffering for weeks through his bad temper, due, I believe because they did not tip him. Yet I felt sorry when the Chief would not allow him to speak saying it must have been serious when the Hospital Corporal complained and if there was another murmur he would know what awaited him at the end of voyage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The poor night boys who had suffered agonies at his hands with beaming faces thanked me for the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still steam ahead the atmosphere getting warmer as we approached the Equator. At time it was fairly warm but not nearly so hot as I expected. Many where the exclamations and wishes to see land only to see Mother Earth once more. After 21 days of Sea blue  sea, green sea, smooth sea. rough sea. quiet + peaceful as a mill pond, rough + boisterous as Biscay Sea with sun shining on it: with moon + stars. Stars that we had known, dipping to the south reminding us of separation from home and friends. Silver sea, sparkling sea. Dark sea blackness that I could almost feel. Sea to the front to the back below + all round us day after day, week after week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sea eternal sea with nothing on the horizon (landscape) save an occasional bird + a darting flying fish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horizon, thou teller of falsehood have often didst thou seem within an hours steam + yet we drew no nearer to you, as we crept along, so didst thou skip away with no object other than to deceive our sight. Well might early explorers have been afraid of you not knowing what thou helds’t beyond that deceiving line. Many thought of hobgoblins, depths of misery, perpendicular heights over which one might fall never to return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sea, sea, sea;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So dark and lonesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speak through the gloom to me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of joy and love and home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell of hearts that are burning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of souls that are yearning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the dark sea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praying for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/9.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/9.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/9.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/9.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/9.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/9.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 9, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/10.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/10.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/10.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/10.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/10.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/10.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 10, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/11.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/11.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/11.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/11.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/11.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/11.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 11, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/12.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/12.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/12.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/12.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/12.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/12.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 12, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/13.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/13.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/13.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/13.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/13.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/13.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 13, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/14.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/14.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/14.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/14.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/14.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/14.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 14, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/15.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/15.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/15.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/15.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/15.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/15.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 15, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/16.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/16.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/16.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/16.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/16.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/16.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 16, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/17.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/17.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/17.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/17.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/17.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/17.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 17, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/18.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/18.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/18.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/18.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/18.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/18.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 18, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/19.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/19.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/19.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/19.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/19.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/19.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 19, transcribed above. Includes a small black and white photo of shafts of light through scattered clouds, over a calm sea&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wednesday, 7/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/07/wednesday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wednesday, 7/11/17" /><published>1917-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/07/wednesday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/07/wednesday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Psalm 145-1
I will extol thee my God,
O king + I will bless thy name for
ever + ever.
New arrangements of 
Orderlies working better.
Wood + King dressings Buguley +
Nichols under Ginger. Fatigue
Have had 2 hrs off in the pm
Enjoyed sun 1st time off since
aboard.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I will extol thee, my God, O king; and I will bless thy name for ever and ever&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Psalm 145:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New arrangements of orderlies working better. Wood and King are doing dressings and Buguley and Nichols are under Ginger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have had 2 hours off in the pm. I enjoyed sun. It was the first time off since aboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/8.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/8.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/8.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/8.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/8.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/8.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 8, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuesday, 6/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/06/tuesday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuesday, 6/11/17" /><published>1917-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/06/tuesday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/06/tuesday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;He hath done all things
well&quot;
Very much better in health
Received supply of pyjamas
for patients. All look happier
Bad cases recovering
Paralysis of hand + arm under
massage treat - by me Showing
signs of improvement.
Took Major to Iso. got canisters
fixed up as a covering.
Put on more orderlies to
lessen my own work. Should get
an hour or two off per day.
Talk of boat being sighted Prob a
star Pte Meers + Burton sharing
Cabin (my permission) Cabin worth £60
for trip. Talk of us remaining
on Transport duty. &quot;He knows&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[in margin]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;9pm Bottom burnt out of steriliser Evidently night O. neglect.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He hath done all things well&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[— Mark 7:37]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very much better in health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received supply of pyjamas for patients. All look happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad cases recovering. Paralysis of hand and arm under massage treatment - by me - showing signs of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took Major to Isolation, got canisters fixed up as a covering. Put on more orderlies to lessen my own work. Should get an hour or two off per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk of boat being sighted. Probably a star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private Meers &amp;amp; Burton sharing cabin (my permission). Cabin worth £60 for trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk of us remaining on Transport duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He knows”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[in margin]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9pm Bottom burnt out of steriliser. Evidently night orderly neglect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/7.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/7.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/7.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/7.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/7.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/7.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 7, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Monday, 5/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/05/monday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Monday, 5/11/17" /><published>1917-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/05/monday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/05/monday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Matt 22-42 Jesus asked What 
think ye of Christ whose son is he?
Got up feeling a bit off
colour. Patients remarked
my frailness. Seasick 10-50
Hos very full. A lot of
work. Given charge of
Isolation. Made changes.
Talk of a 3rd stripe so
that I can meal at Sgts Mess
Not at all well tonight.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[later]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Quit a stir as to reason
of date (Antipodes)
Plenty of general work
Wondering how all are at
home expecially Clare
Very poorly all day but kept
about
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jesus asked, “What think ye of Christ? whose son is he?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Matthew 22:42&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up later than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got up feeling a bit off colour. Patients remarked on my frailness. Seasick 10:50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hospital is very full. A lot of work. Given charge of Isolation. Made changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talk of a 3rd stripe so that I can meal at Sargent’s Mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not at all well tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[later]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite a stir as to reason of date (Antipodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of general work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wondering how all are at home especially Clare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very poorly all day but kept about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/6.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/6.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/6.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/6.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/6.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/6.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 6, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunday, 4/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/04/sunday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunday, 4/11/17" /><published>1917-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/04/sunday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/04/sunday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Matt 16-16 &quot;Thou art the Christ; 
the son of the living God.&quot;
Up later than usual
Everybody available for
Church parade. I had a chat
to several of the patients. Gave
a number of tracts out which were
well received.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thou art the Christ; the son of the living God.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Matthew 16:16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up later than usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody available for Church parade. I had a chat to several of the patients. Gave a number of tracts out which were well received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/5.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 5, second half transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Saturday, 3/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/03/saturday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Saturday, 3/11/17" /><published>1917-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/03/saturday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/03/saturday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Matt 16-15
Whom say ye that I am?

Hos work as usual
Fire alarm sounded at
4-30. Each man had
lifebelt. Very sick patients
stretchers. Given for practise.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whom say ye that I am?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Matthew 16:15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hospital work as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fire alam sounded at 4:30. Each man had a lifebelt. Very sick patients were on stretchers. It was given for practise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/5.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/5.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 5, first half transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Friday, 2/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/02/friday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Friday, 2/11/17" /><published>1917-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/02/friday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/02/friday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Psalm 103-1
Bless the Lord, O my
soul + all that is
within me, bless his holy name.
Slept till 6am. Did not
deliver mail to boats. None
in sight. Air becoming
warmer. Supposed to be within
Tropics in 2 days. Evidently
Via Panama. Work all
going smoothly. Night Orderlies
not Comp, but willing. Seem
to know very little.
Evidently to take full charge
of Isolation tomorrow. Am not
at all pleased with present
condition. Wrote 2 letter for
Pte Greely.
2 Pneumonia cases getting on
fairly well.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord, O my soul: and all that is within me, bless his holy name.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Psalm 103:1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slept till 6am. Did not deliver mail to boats, none in sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Air becoming warmer. Supposed to be within Tropics in 2 days, evidently via Panama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work all going smoothly. Night orderlies not competent but willing. Seem to know very little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently to take full charge of Isolation tomorrow. Am not at all pleased with present condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote 2 letters for Private Greely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two pneumonia cases getting on fairly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/4.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/4.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/4.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/4.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/4.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/4.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 4, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thursday, 1/11/17</title><link href="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/01/thursday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thursday, 1/11/17" /><published>1917-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>1917-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/01/thursday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cathywise.net/elias-augustus-brough/1917/11/01/thursday.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcription&quot;&gt;Transcription&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;John 9-4.
&quot;I must work the works of
Him that sent me.&quot;
Had beautiful day.
Two professing Christians as
orderlies. General talks over
the Word. One an ex Rev.
Hope to speak more on truths.
Hazy idea of Baptism.
Better method of obtaining food.
Have whole charge of both Hos.
Made several alterations.
Had to remind Isolation that I
would not; + would not have
bad language used.
Think it better to pluck it in
bud.
Evidently bound for America.
More patients. About 24.
Still very well.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[in margin]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Received £1 borrowed by G SSB With thanks
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanded&quot;&gt;Expanded&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I must work the works of Him that sent me&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— John 9:4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had a beautiful day. Two professing Christians as orderlies. General talks over the Word. One an ex Reverend. Hope to speak more on truths. Hazy idea of Baptism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better method of obtaining food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have whole charge of both hospitals. Made several alterations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Had to remind Isolation that I would not; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; not have bad language used. Think it better to pluck it in the bud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidently bound for America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More patients, about 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still very well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[in margin]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received £1 borrowed by G SSB With thanks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/images/diary/photos/3.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_100//images/diary/photos/3.jpeg 100w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_200//images/diary/photos/3.jpeg 200w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_500//images/diary/photos/3.jpeg 500w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_700//images/diary/photos/3.jpeg 700w, https://res.cloudinary.com/cathywise/image/upload/c_limit,w_1000//images/diary/photos/3.jpeg 1000w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; alt=&quot;photo of page 3, transcribed above&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Transcription</summary></entry></feed>